[Music]
Hello everyone. I am Christina and with
me I have Vessa.
>> Hi everyone. My name is Vessa and I will
be doing the demo today.
>> Today we are excited to introduce some
powerful new capabilities in Business
Central that will give our customers and
partners more control and flexibility
and confidence when preparing for
upcoming updates. With this feature, you
can now take a copy of your production
data into a sandbox environment and then
upgrade that sandbox to a preview
version of the next Business Central
release. So, why is this a game changer?
Let's break it down. So, um this will
allow you to um pre prepare for the
preview with confidence and reduce your
risks and stay ahead of the curb. and um
whether your customers are preparing for
a change or a partner that is supporting
multiple tenants, this feature will help
you deliver smooth transitions and
better outcomes. Let's dig into a demo.
Uh so I will be doing a short demo of
this feature and um here on my uh
computer I have opened the business
central admin center and uh I have my
sandbox environment uh which is
currently on version 26.4.
I can see that there is a version
available to 27.0 0 preview and I can
select that by going to modify expanding
the target versions and then selecting
the 27.0 preview that is currently
available. Uh so you can select the date
for the update when it should run and
there is this box right under the target
version that has a few links. One of
them is the learn more page and then we
also have the link to the preview terms.
So once you have selected a date you can
just go ahead and schedule the update
and then you can see that there is an
update to the preview version that is
scheduled. So during the preview period
we automatically reschedu the up the
failed updates um every seven days. Um
and once we are outside of the preview
period, your environment will be uh
automatically scheduled to update to the
very next official version and the
preview version is not visible on the
admin center anymore. That is what I
had. Thank you for this lovely
demonstration. Um before we close, I
just want to share some few helpful tips
to uh keep in mind when updating to the
previous sandboxes. So these
environments are a really great
fantastic way to explore what's coming
in Business Central. Um since this is a
preview, um please um be aware that some
functionality uh might be changing uh
some a little bit. Um but this is of
course part of a preview um experience.
We will try and upgrade your preview uh
sandbox if possible. Um, and be aware
that after our preview ends, uh, your
sandbox, uh, will be cleaned up, uh,
with the normal grace period. Um, use it
to learn, test, and prepare. Uh, do not
use it for live operations and, um, be
informed that we are not sending email
notifications out for preview updates.
Uh so you should check your app insights
for telemetry and please ask to please
reach out to our other uh general
business central resources uh on AKMSPC
all our YouTube channel if you have
questions go to yama and follow us on
LinkedIn and or join our office hours to
learn more. Thank you for this demo and
thank you for watching all this was it
for us today.
>> Yes, thank you very much.